lamrim means a general presentation
of the whole path to become a good
person
and we're studying right now
this week to become a bodhisattva
and there's a song i can't play it it's
illegal online
but there's a beautiful song uh
bodhisattva
who won't you take me and
it's a rock and roll song good guitar
part for ben gibson
incredible guitar part uh
and i remember hearing that song
bodhisattva and
i didn't know this was before i
i met the tibetans and i didn't know
what's a buddhism but i like the word
somehow i like the word maybe you're
maybe you have this experience
that uh the word is attractive or the
word sounds beautiful oh
he's a real bodhisattva you know it
means he's really nice
person really good to other people
so we've been studying uh and by the way
it doesn't matter what religion you are
i don't care
you're christian or you're muslim or
you're buddhist
you're a hindu it doesn't matter
every tradition has this idea
like a bodhisattva super nice person
super super nice person you know so i
think
every country and every culture
appreciates special nice people like the
aci volunteers
or the gold club organizers
you are already police officers in that
sense okay
so today i get to teach the bodhisattvas
about
bodhisattva okay and
in the lamrim a story came
and and the author of the lamrim
said you should learn to do
an act of truth
and you can base it on being a
bodhisattva
okay that was in the long run you should
learn to do an act of
and you can base it on being a body
surfer
for example it's like the story
of the bodhisattva whose name was
sada
[Music]
can't stop crying his name is crying all
the time
mr sadapra
mr crying all the time he can't stop
crying all the time
you know and when i heard that name
the first time i remember i
i enjoyed teaching because i remember
learning everything myself i was not
born as a buddhist
and i didn't grow up in a buddhist
country and and all of these stories
were new for me
so i remember the first time hearing
about the bodhisattva who couldn't stop
crying
and i don't know about you but in my
mind i had a picture
of a very compassionate guy you know
super compassionate and whenever he
thinks about
hungry people refugees or any problems
in the world he start to cry you know i
had this picture in my mind
and it's wrong
okay that's not what he's called then
all right
so that's the first thing i want to say
about his story
he's not calm mr bodhisattva
who cannot stop crying because he's
compassionate that's not why he's crying
in the story
okay and then uh
the lamrim says he did an act of truth
and he fixed his body based on being a
bodhisattva
he did an act of truth and he fixed his
body
based based on being a bodhisattva
okay so what does it mean to do an act
of truth
most of you guys heard about it
and this is not just buddhism this is
all of india
and all of south asia there's an
old tradition that truth has a big power
truth has a extremely
huge power the telling truth
telling the truth in your life has a
huge power
okay in fact that power
you can harness it it's like a wind what
do you call those things
windmill turbine yeah
you know we just went to california me
and veronica
and we went to the beach but on the way
you can see these big
wind turbines you know and they are
harnessing out energy
that was lost before right for thousands
of years
the wind blew across the arizona desert
nobody tried to catch it you know nobody
tried to make electricity
and now we are grabbing that energy out
of the sky
and and some of the lights in this room
are powered by those
wind turbines the electricity that comes
from them right
some percent of arizona power
comes from those wind turbines the act
of truth
is very similar you know we tell the
truth
all day sometimes or partly true
and you can grab that energy and you can
turn it into other
in it you can turn it into power for
your life you see you every time you
tell the truth
you can grab that energy and you can use
that power
so you can you can say for example
if it's true i got up at
three o'clock in the morning the aci
director got up at three o'clock in the
morning
to do a to do a broadcast
for dci not for acr
okay uh it is true i was a nice guy this
morning
then by that power i should have the
best breakfast
in bowie arizona which is not very
difficult
to have the best one okay
you know you can take the wind power
the wind and turn it into some energy
okay that's called act of truth okay
what's the
most famous act of truth in ancient
india
if it's true i love my neighbor then
yeah then the largest river maybe in the
world i think
should go backwards for a couple hours
and there are stories of
farmers who went to the saints
and said stop it already and the saints
are like what
he said stop turning back the goddess
river we're trying to irrigate our
fields
and the river is flowing backwards can
you just stop it
stop this act of truth stuff you know so
we're gonna describe an act of truth all
right
you can do it any time in your day
in your day you can say if it's true
that that i volunteered to help acio if
it's true
i'm supporting the gold club you know
if it's true i'm saving this ancient
wisdom
then may my ant's cancer get better
see i mean you can use that wind energy
for other things okay and and you should
try it
okay if it's true that i spent
a year helping as an aci volunteer or if
it's true i spent a year
helping the gold clubs then
then my my my aunt or someone who's sick
someone who's sad
they should be happier i give them that
energy okay got it
so here's a famous act of truth here's a
story
it's gonna take a while okay so get your
coffee
and your nutella toast and
just relax and have fun if you want to
turn it off
if you want to go to the bathroom go to
the bathroom come back if you want to
eat breakfast eat breakfast come back
if you want to go back to bed i don't
that's fine too
except the people in the room
okay and let's just have fun today is
fun today is relaxed
today is for the volunteers and and it's
to thank you and i do thank you very
much
okay all right here we go we're gonna
project this to tibetan uh
somebody was complaining about me for
something i don't remember
but uh i and of course when when someone
complains about you
you you think about it so i was thinking
about it in my important
room after i
went to the toilet and but i was
thinking
there's one thing about this tradition
you know especially diamond mountain
tradition
everything we teach here comes directly
from the ancient books we don't teach
anything
nothing here that doesn't come from the
ancient books
and we put the ancient books the
original language
in the in the class materials you see i
mean
so you can't say uh this is not what the
buddha taught this
is it's it's directly
the the ancient book is in the class
manual
you know we're the only place in the
world that does it i think
every there's 30 000 pages
of aci and other materials
and each sentence has the original
language
with it and you can check it you can
look at it okay
and that's the amazing thing about you
gold club people
because you import the ancient books
geshe-la can teach directly from the
ancient books okay
so you're very very important okay
so we're going to study directly from
the ancient books okay
today and that's just the way i like to
do it
and and it's not geshe michael and it's
not my idea
it's called buddha okay
and and this story because in the alarm
rim
the llama says it's like the story
of the bodhisattva who couldn't stop
crying
how he fixed his body with
an act of truth based on
buddy to the body surface ideal and then
he went on he didn't tell the story then
i'm like
we don't know the story you guys know
the story you grew up in tibet we don't
know the story
could you please give us the story and
then
what's cool about john brady's a-l-l
database that bodhisattva's name is mr
cannot stop crying if geshela
wants to find the story in 300
000 books which is 15 million pages
something like that i can just
say give me the story of the bodhisattva
who couldn't stop crying
and it comes within two seconds i get it
within two seconds
okay it's a mic miracle okay but
somebody has to type
to type it the person who types it has
to eat breakfast
the breakfast costs money got it
that's why we're fundraising okay all
right here we go
you ready paul
now this is part of a long long story
it's deep in the middle of the 8 000
verses
which is a thousand pages of ancient
tibetan
okay and i found it in about five
seconds
okay thanks to you guys thanks to you
gold club people okay
then the great bodhisattva named
can't stop crying in tibetan it's doctor
[Music]
he went to the town square
like in bowie that's that
place right he went to the town square
to to do what he had to do
okay he had to do something and if
if you know this
sutras hundreds of thousands of lines
about emptiness in the middle of those
emptiness explanation there are stories
there are beautiful stories and and we
someday we should translate them
okay so here's his story he by the way
he was
a normal guy he was having a normal life
and then he woke up one day probably to
do a 3am
dci talk and he heard the sound in his
ear it said
go east walk east he's like what
who's talking and there's nobody there
and then it just was quiet and he
he you know he finished his dci
broadcast and then he's gonna go for
breakfast and then he hears this
i told you walk east and he's like who
is that
you know and he keeps hearing this
message
in his ear walk is you must walk east
and then he's like finally he can't
stand it anymore and he just
gets a backpack and he figures his
iphone
wears east and he he went to the east
he started walking to the east you know
and he doesn't know why
nobody told him why you know and he just
kept walking
and he believed the message he got
i'm supposed to slow down i was going
slow
no he believed
the message and as he's walking
across diamond mountain desert
he starts to have this vision of a
teacher
sitting in a house
teaching emptiness he has he gets this
strong
picture of a teacher
at that moment teaching in a small house
somewhere to the east and
and then he starts walking faster and
day after day he's walking to the east
and this vision gets stronger and
stronger you know like as he's walking
he can see this teacher he can't hear
but he hears the he sees the teacher
talking and he's like and he he starts
to understand
that he's if he keeps walking east
he's going to meet the teacher you see
what i mean then he gets to this
town small town and he senses
the teacher's house is on the other side
of the town
he made it you know he made it to the
teacher's house
you know and then he's like
i did it you know today i'm gonna meet
this teacher
today i will get emptiness teachings
and then he's like oh no i gotta
i can't go to him empty-handed you know
i gotta have something to you know you
you can't meet a teacher without some
flowers
or some pizza or other important
offerings
you know so he's like but he spent all
his money on the road he has no money
he's entering the town with nothing and
and here's the story here we pick up
okay ready he's gonna do his act of
truth
for pizza okay
indian pizza all right
he went to the market square
main cinder mission
who wants to buy me
he goes to the middle of the market like
that mercado
in uh guadalajara uh i forget what it's
called
yeah next to where all the you have to
go past where aldo lives or something
so anyway uh he's like who wants to buy
me
who wants to buy me i need money you
know
it's very funny he's sitting there like
me for sale me for sale
okay and jack doc you guys had dog
because it's part of shravaka
he proclaimed in the market okay
person started yelling dude
there was a demon standing nearby
invisible demon you know and he says hmm
this bodhisattva mr can't stop crying
we don't know why he can't why he's
crying yet okay but you're starting to
get a clue
this guy is gonna sell his body
so that he can get some offerings to
offer to the
great bodhisattva whose name is dharm
udgata okay
it means uh high dharma mr haidarma
okay he wants to honor
his teacher with some flowers or
something
and that's why he's selling his body
this morning
okay uh jeeta chandra samba samba chamba
if this guy learns the perfection of
wisdom
what's a demon gonna think disaster
what happened when the truck hit the
lady with the big butt
this asked her
never mind uh sorry
this is what your husband does in the
morning okay
uh if this guy studies emptiness
we're in trouble the demons are in
trouble okay
he will quickly reach total buddhahood
if he keeps studying emptiness if he
gets contact
with this great teacher and studies the
profession of wisdom
which is emptiness and and love together
right
then it's going to be a disaster he'll
become a buddha then we have another
problem
we got another buddha in the world okay
tabla keba and he will learn top like
about 100
yeah he will learn not papaya
upaya he will learn how to do
tricky good things which is worse than
being a buddha
okay you also deal with your thing he
will get used to doing that
de tobage topper he will
gain an ocean worth of teachings from
this teacher
very dangerous
then uh
people like me are gonna get in trouble
he's gonna give us trouble okay uh
yen then tom jackie potter to chimba
jaso tobago
he will reach the other side of the
ocean of good qualities prajnaparam
okay there's some mumbo
taking shape our gear and then he will
be able to serve many people effectively
okay that's a problem
so
means he will pass beyond my clutches i
won't be able to
get him he will go
he'll be moving too fast for me to catch
him
the demons right uh dollar tip or yorkie
dakidi parche
i should give this guy a party
i should create an obstacle for him
right i better stop him now
like okay the demon's like what's the
what's the bodhisattva doing
who wants me who wants me you know he
says i gotta stop this guy
he arranged it so that everybody in the
market
couldn't hear what he was saying
got it the body stopped us in the
marketplace going
and everybody's like wow look at the
weird guys he's doing like that but he
can't hear anything
you know he arranged it so the sound was
blocked
okay uh but did i
yells a dip he blocked the sound from
so people can see him
but they don't know what he's talking
saying
300 tell me what happens next to the
bodhisattva
300 guess they won the 300
say it he starts to cry
out of frustration god damn
i try to get my body away and nobody can
hear me
then he can't stop crying okay got it
now you guys know a big secret
from the perfection of wisdom sutras the
bodhisattva who cries all the time
is not crying out of compassion he's
crying out of
frustration
i do this while at home i get in trouble
okay
he's so he went in a corner and started
crying
okay
all i wanted to do was make some flower
offers to my new teacher
and how he was trying to sell my body
lunya
i don't even have the karma to
sell my own body he's like
my karma really sucks you know
like my karma is so bad i can't even
sell my own bun
he's like that can't camera means
by the way camera is keyhood
i'm a really lousy person in the whole
world
i i can't even sell my own finger
you know what's how bad is that okay
all right daenerys
then chakra came which is the lord
it's the wombo of the indra right the
lord of the gods
shakura means destroyer of a hundred
cities but he's powerful
okay super powerful dude
deva
is it possible that this guy's really
willing to sell his body to get some
flowers
to meet a teacher he never met because
he had some vision of
you know that he's gonna learn emptiness
is it plausible
this is weird who's thinking that
shakur king of the gods deva david
number one
saba prints itself i doubt it you know
i mean come on that's a little extreme
chanting
i will test him who's talking
i'll test him let's see if he was really
willing to sell his body
you know let's see if he's sincere then
maybe we'll help him out
okay cool all right
chakra thought to himself
then the lord of the gods emanated
as a teenage punk
okay trump said q okay he's like a
i don't know party on a good day you
know hey dude
hey dude he's like a cool young man
handsome cool young man
uh okay he emanate this as a normal
and he approached the bodhisattva who
can't stop crying
so they only change
why are you sitting here crying what's
the problem
you know why are you so sad what's going
on you know
thank you then he said hey cool handsome
young man
nae lu tzungwaduna i was trying to sell
my body
ludin but i
i can't even do that i failed
even to sell myself you know
so i'm depressed i'm saying
chakra in the form of a hip young man
hip handsome young man said hey
ricky poo okay hey noble noble
young man kid chi chin dagnit someone do
why do you want to sell yourself what's
the what are you doing
i want the dharma so i'm selling my body
that's that's why i'm selling my body i
want the dumb
and it's improper to
seek the dharma without honoring the
teacher
it's improper i can't it's not it's not
right
the reason i'm so upset is that i was
trying to sell my body
to buy some flowers and i failed
something's wrong nobody's even
listening to me
okay
i must be mr
zero good karma if i can't even sell my
own body
okay uh shiraki products
all i wanted was to learn emptiness
papa cha du semba samba champapna
and i wanted to honor my new teacher
what did we call him
[Music]
hip young guy said to the
bodhisattva
hey look i can't
use you i don't need a person
okay i don't need like a slave or you
know what am i gonna do with you
why should i buy you you know it's
useless to me
like one more mouth to feed in my house
you know
i don't need you okay
what's that mean you guys but
i was gonna do a special fire often this
morning
i was gonna do a special fire offering
this morning say children
this is a hindu ancient hindu not now
this okay
ancient hindu fire offering and they
need
parts of a human being they need a heart
they need some lungs they need some
brain
they need some kidney okay
to throw in the fire one by one
okay this is an ancient terrible custom
they used to do it with cows
they would cut up the cow and and offer
parts of the cow to the fire this is the
ancient
homa it's one kind of hormone it's not
all the hummus but
you know also and they would cut they
would kill a cow
and take out his heart and then take out
his lungs and one by one
so look i don't need a person but i
could use your parts
okay i could use your heart if you want
to sell me your heart you know
we can talk okay
i need a human heart i need some human
blood
i need some bone i need some marrow
from you okay
and i will pay you the cost of them okay
and then you can before i cut you up you
can go buy some flowers or whatever
okay all right
today i went from worst karma to best
karma
someone wants to buy my lungs and my
heart and my blood
dang i'm so lucky you know okay
daki luna shiraki powder to chimp
if i sell my body today
you know these parts maybe
definitely it'll make the karma for me
to get
emptiness teachings later okay it's
worth it
it's worth it he's very happy you also
don't belong i will become a buddha
nyam today
sender to governor terms
he was happy he was super happy
he was super super duper happy and he
said
deal it's a deal okay
and transactions
do whatever you want with my body yay
okay
then the guy says wait wait wait let's
get the contract straight here
you know how much you want for your body
den de la dicke miso times iq
i'll take whatever you're offering i
mean i can buy some plot
give me a couple bucks i could buy some
flowers
you know before you cut me up you know
mr couldn't stop crying got so excited
he grabs a sharp knife
and he starts going at it okay
he he's so excited he can't wait for the
he's like give me a knife
you know by the way this is a buddhist
teaching you are not meant to do it
okay so i don't want to hear that
somebody in moscow
cut their fingers off and sent them to
somebody in france
okay bad idea okay we are not
at this level repeat we are not
at this level repeat you will not be
at this level anytime soon you
you are not allowed to hurt your
precious body one scratch okay
these are old stories okay and
always some fool somewhere says i'm i'm
at that level
you are not okay and don't do it it's
stupid
your body's very precious you have to
take good care of your body
if you feel like stabbing your body
right now go do a hard yoga
and get healthier and that's that's the
level we're at
okay
[Music]
he grabbed a knife and he shoved it into
his right
arm and he started to let the blood out
okay
he took his right thigh and
took the knife and and stripped off the
meat
from the thigh until he exposed the bone
down to the bone okay sigma means he
exposed the bone of his right side
now very vagina
very vagina that's why i like this story
okay
very vagina there was a beautiful maiden
who was the daughter of a local
businessman
okay the beautiful daughter of a local
she was signing herself on the roof
of their expensive
fifth avenue apartment she's stunning
herself on the roof
around the square like central park like
john brady's old apartment
and she's like wait what's going on down
there
you know she's like getting a sun pan
she's probably she's in a bikini i guess
and she's like what's going on down
there you know
i'm just kidding okay i'm sure she's in
there sorry
but i'm gonna talk mama wow what's the
guy doing he's cutting his arm up he's
cutting his leg up
you know she can't hear what's going on
she saw the bone under the thigh when he
got down to the white
bone she's like she thought to herself
i gotta get down there and ask this guy
what's he doing
what why is he cutting himself up like
that you know
i gotta get downstairs and go out to the
square and ask him what's going on
why are you what are you doing okay
[Music]
then she descended to the street she
crossed the street
she went into the market square
she went up to the young bodhisattva and
said
what are you doing ricky piu
dani laditab chattanooga
what are you doing to yourself what are
you going to do with the flesh that
you've cut off
what are you going to do with all this
blood what are you going to do in the
bones
oh young lady i am in selling my body
okay to this nice young man shiraki
product
and i will give this money
as an offering for emptiness teachings
and bodhisattva teachings perfection
wisdom
and i will honor my teacher high dharma
okay my new teacher who he hasn't met
yet he just had a vision of him right
here then the young lady said to the
bodhisattva
ricky
what are you going to get out of it you
know
you you sell your body you get some
offerings
you go to the class what are you gonna
what what's going to happen then why are
you going to the class
special ways of getting dharma done like
gold clubs
okay
when i learned how to be a bodhisattva
and when i learned emptiness i would
become a buddha that will make me a
buddha
and then i can really help people then i
can really help people
and my body will change as if the
alchemical elictor had been poured on it
my meat body will turn to a rainbow body
i will have a indestructible diamond
body
i like to call it living diamond i will
be living diamond
i will become living diamonds
i will get the 80
sorry i will get the 32 major marks of
the buddha
i will get the 80 secondary signs of a
buddhist body
light will emanate from me in a halo
to the a dom dom means from finger to
finger if you're six feet high
okay i will have a dome halo
i'll have a six foot halo okay
i started
i will get all the amazing qualities of
a buddha
and he lists them okay
he lists all of them if you're
interested in them go
read ben cramer mix nuts translation
coming out soon we spent how long tim
and a year on them okay
something like that that last part of
the book
[Music]
um
the daughter of the rich man said to the
bodhisattva
your description of what you're gonna
do with this money it's amazing
incredible okay no time
awesome
[Music]
i would like to do the same you know
that sounds
cool i i want that too i also want that
that's beautiful right
[Music]
so hey i have a suggestion
let's buy you some gold
and let's buy you some jewels
and let's get you some pearls and let's
get you some baiduria
lapis lazuli and let's get you some
silver
and let's get you some musala garba
which i don't know what it is
okay it's not masala karma okay
it's some kind of gemstone lohita raga
i just gave a dharma name to elizabeth
babanova and this is it okay elizabeth
here's the name
lohitaraga okay uh the
the ruby the lady i'll give you rubies
shell i will give you rock crystals
method i will give you flowers incense
perfumes garlands of flowers
arnica sam
from nile it's exactly
uh powdered incense
curse some golden clothes duke some
parasols gensom victory banners
dubu sacred bells but then
big more banners marmae
butter lamps anything you need
i'll do it i'll take care of it okay
i'll get you whatever you need i'll pay
for everything
please don't cut yourself up i think she
fell in love with him already
okay and probably mutual dark young kid
and let's go together to the arya
you and me let's go ask him for
teachings together
isn't it a beautiful story now you know
why i wanted to tell this story
it's so romantic
let's go meet the arya together
i will be your constant companion
[Music]
stripped off the disguise
and showed himself as iron man
or you know in a deva form you know so
he strips off this
hip young man this guy's and
suddenly he's this golden deva standing
in front of the bodhisattva
good job i tested you and you passed
okay men kidding
that's exactly how people get to be
buddhas by doing what you're doing
you're so smart lana
[Music]
let me tell you the truth i don't need
your heart and your marrow
and your blood and your liver and can
you know i was just joking
i don't really mean it okay
i was just checking you out i've just
seen if you were serious
go get the ultimate you're done with
your test
you know go go go pluck the ultimate
from this llama
okay you're free you know the deal's off
go go get the highest goal de
de la me page
there's a little side story the police
officer says you teach me
you're so glorious you know you're so
amazing
this deva you are so golden
light huge beautiful deva
you teach me the professional wisdom
i'm a powerful being but i don't have
that much power
to teach emptiness i don't have that
power
okay to teach you love i don't have that
power i can
crush a planet in my fingers but i don't
have the power to teach you emptiness
and i don't have i can't teach you love
somebody else has to do that
you're gonna have to go to that teacher
okay he has the power i don't have that
i can crush a planet
like this but i don't have the power to
teach you emptiness okay
uh
[Music]
but you have the power to fix my body
right i just cut off my
thigh meat you get the story now
what are we supposed to be talking about
how an act of truth based on
bodhichitta intention and
and so the bodhisattva says to the deva
but but you know before i go to the
teacher could you just fix this leg and
this arm can you can you fix this up can
you do that much
do an act of truth young man do an act
of truth you can heal yourself
heal thyself okay heal yourself
how say if it's true i want to help
all the beings in the universe then may
my leg be healed
and may my arm be healed okay got it
then i can tell me somebody you want me
for
if you do this act of truth something
will happen
then in a single instant the young man's
arm grew back
and his leg grew back and he became
purely healthy and
normal and walked to his teacher
[Music]
that's the story and again uh so anyway
i hope you found it inspiring i
i love this story that's why i wanted to
tell it separately
and i think there's a lot of
lessons for us there you know there's a
lesson for all of us there
okay